Guide to the John Luke Bray Methodist Sermons, 1907-1938 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John Luke Bray Methodist Sermons 1907-1938 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bray, John Luke
0.4 linear feet Extent: 78 Items
Methodist minister, active in southern Virginia in the early twentieth century. Collection of 74 unpublished typewritten sermons and texts for prayer meetings assembled by a Methodist minister active in Virginia in the early twentieth century. Although no author's name is given, from church appointment records it is almost certain that the minister is John Luke Bray (1871-1938). The sermons were given from 1907 to 1938 in localities in southern Virginia (almost all in Danville, Crewe, South Boston, Richmond, and Norfolk); the earliest sermon was given in Shawnee, Oklahoma. At times the minister may have been using churches that offered space to other denominations. The sermon notes, typed in red and black and typically two to four pages, document the typical style of Methodist preaching in the South and sometimes refer to social or economic issues. Each envelope enclosing the sermon text is marked with the title and when and where preached; most have multiple dates and locations. There are also a few miscellaneous items, including newspaper clippings, handwritten notes, and one leaf with an undated hymn with words by A. W. Davis, entitled "Over the Top With Jesus," dedicated to a "Rev. D. H. Kenney." Some fragile items have been photocopied. Arranged in two series: Prayer Meetings and Sermons.
RL.00147
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The John Luke Bray Methodist Sermons were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in April 2007.
Biographical Note
The minister who authored these sermons was undoubtedly a member of the Methodist Church South, and from church appointment records he is almost certainly John Luke Bray. According to Bray's obituary in the Virginia Conference Annual (1938), he was born in 1871 in Gloucester County, Virginia to John and Sarah Luke Bray, and entered the Methodist ministry in the Virginia Conference at the age of 18. He was at Randolph-Macon College for an unspecified period but did not graduate. At some point he was reportedly Superintendent of the Masonic Orphanage in Richmond. He married Pauline Clements of Gloucester, Virginia early in his career. In 1901 he left for the West, and seems to have been minister of the Methodist Church in Shawnee, Oklahoma (then Indian territory) in 1906. He returned to Virginia in 1907; a year later Taylor University in Indiana had conferred on him the Divinity Degree. Going by the sermons that survive in this collection, by 1911 he was preaching in Virginia. His first appointment may have been in Lambert's Point, Virginia (near Norfolk). He then was appointed to various large congregations in Richmond and the Norfolk area, then migrated to smaller churches in Southern Virginia. He died in 1938, perhaps in Crewe, Virginia, a small community where he held his last appointment, and is buried in Richmond.
Collection Overview
Collection of 74 unpublished typewritten sermons and texts for prayer meetings (also called sermons) assembled by a Methodist minister active in Virginia in the early twentieth century. Although no author's name is given, from church appointment records it is almost certain that the minister is John Luke Bray (1871-1938). The sermons were given from 1907 to 1938 in localities in southern Virginia (almost all in Danville, Crewe, South Boston, Richmond, and Norfolk); the earliest sermon (1907) was given in Shawnee, Oklahoma. The minister served for several years in each church, the last sermons of 1936-1938 being given in the Methodist Church in the railroad town of Crewe, Va., which possibly also served a Baptist congregation, an arrangement not unusual in rural areas. The sermon notes, typed in red and black and typically two to four pages in length, offer evidence of the typical style of preaching in Methodist churches in the South and sometimes refer to social or economic issues. Each envelope enclosing the sermon text is marked with the title, taken from a Biblical text, and when and where preached; most have multiple dates and locations. Most envelopes are marked in a corner as "Sermon Notes," but some are labeled "Prayer Meetings," with the text inside still labeled by the minister as a sermon. There are also a few miscellaneous items, including newspaper clippings, handwritten notes, and one leaf with an undated hymn with words by A. W. Davis, entitled "Over the Top With Jesus," dedicated to a "Rev. D. H. Kenney." Some fragile items have been photocopied. Arranged in two series: Prayer Meetings and Sermons, with the bulk of the sermons housed in the latter group. Within each series, arranged in Biblical order.
Subject Headings
Bray, John Luke; Methodist Church -- Sermons -- 20th century; Methodist Church -- Virginia; Methodist Church -- Virginia -- History; Methodist Church -- Virginia -- Clergy; Hymns; Preaching -- History; Sermons, American; Sermons, American -- Virginia; Sermons, American -- 20th century; Prayer meetings -- Virginia; Virginia -- Religious life and customs; Virginia -- Social conditions; Sermons
Related Material
United Methodist Church Records, 1784-1984 bulk 1800-1940
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Contents of Collection
- Prayer Meetings Series, 1930-1938, (11 items)
  - Exodus 34:28-29, Result of the Luminous Life (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Aug. 19 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Dec. 6 (Box 1)
  - Psalm 51:12, A Prayer for Restored Purity
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 July 8 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1936 June 17 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1938 Jan. 5 (Box 1)
  - Psalm 55:22, The Sustaining Rest of the Lord
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 July 22 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1936 July 8 (Box 1)
  - Psalm 56:11, The Soul's Confidence in God
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Aug. 5 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Dec. 12 (Box 1)
  - Proverbs 4:23, The Duty of Keeping the Heart (no location given) (Box 1)
  - Acts 27:23, Being God's and Serving God
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1930 Apr. 30 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Oct. 3 (Box 1)
  - I Corinthians 16:13, The Making for Strength
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Aug. 8 (Box 1)
  - II Corinthians 6:1, Working Together with Him
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Aug. 26 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Sept. 5 (Box 1)
  - II Corinthians 7:5-7, Never-the-less God
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Jan. 24 (Box 1)
    - Crewe, Va., 1937 Jan. 27 (Box 1)
  - Ephesians 3:23-21, The Family in Earth and Heaven
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Mar. 30 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Dec. 13 (Box 1)
  - Revelation 1:18, Christ the Key to Death and Grave
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Apr. 1 (Box 1)
- Sermons Series, 1907-1938 and undated, (65 items)
  - Genesis 5:27, The Dimensional Life (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Mar. 15 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Aug. 27 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 May 16 (Box 1)
  - Genesis 37:19-20, The Dreamer and His Dreams
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1924 Sept. 21 (Box 1)
  - Genesis 40:12, Writing the Pages of Life
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1922 July 9 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1923 Sept. 23 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1927 June 26 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Dec. 2 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1936 Sept. 13 (Box 1)
  - Exodus 32:31-32, The Interruptions of Life
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1921 Feb. 20 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1922 Nov. 19 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1926 Nov. 28 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Jan. 8 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Jan. 29 (Box 1)
    - Union Service, Baptist Church, 1934 July 1 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 April 11 (Box 1)
  - Exodus 35:20-21, The Response of the People
    - Lambert's Point, Norfolk, Va., 1912 Sept. 15 (Box 1)
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1915 June 27 (Box 1)
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1918 June 9 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1926 May 23 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1929 June 9 (Box 1)
  - Deuteronomy 8:2, Remembering the Way of the Lord
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1920 Feb. 22 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1923 Mar. 25 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1926 Apr. 4 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1929 May 12 21 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Apr. 8 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1938 Jan. 23 (Box 1)
  - Joshua 1:2, The Call From God for a Crisis
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Apr. 6 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Sept. 20 (Box 1)
  - I Samuel 7:12, What the Church Stands For
    - Clay St., Norfolk Va., 1914 Oct. 12 (Box 1)
  - I Kings 4:29, Supreme Yearning of the Heart
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1921 Oct. 2 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1923 Mar. 4 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1926 Mar. 30 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 July 15 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 May 27 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 May 2 (Box 1)
  - II Kings 2:10, We Need a New Vision of Christ
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 May 17 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Oct. 15 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 May 16 (Box 1)
  - II Kings 10:15, A Correct Heart Required
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1915 Dec. 5 (Box 1)
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1918 June 30 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1927 Feb. 13 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 July 5 (Box 1)
    - Omega, Halifax County, Va., 1935 July 8 (Box 1)
  - Job 10:1-2, The Education of Sorrow
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1924 Oct. 5 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Sept. 23 (Box 1)
  - Psalm 24:7-10, The Gates are Open (no location given) (Box 1)
  - Psalm 34:3, What Can The Church Do For Us
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Mar. 8 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Sept. 30 (Box 1)
  - Psalm 47:9, The Shields of the Soul, clipped with Romans 8:28, II Timothy 2:14 and Hebrews 10:35
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 June 24 (Box 1)
    - South Boston, Va., 1934 July 14 (Box 1)
  - Psalm 51:12, Finding the Lost Radiance
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1936 Apr. 19 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1936 Nov. 22 (Box 1)
  - Psalm 51:12, Suffered a Great Loss
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Jan. 25 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Jan. 29 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1936 Dec. 6 (Box 1)
  - Psalm 104:26, Two Forces Battling for Supremacy
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Feb. 28 (Box 1)
  - Proverbs 4:2-4, Fond Memories of Home
    - Lambert's Point, Norfolk, Va., 1913 Oct. 19 (Box 1)
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1915 May 9 (Box 1)
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1918 May 12 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1920 May 9 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1925 May 12 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1929 May 12 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 May 14 (Box 1)
  - Proverbs 16:16, More Valuable Than Gold
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1926 Aug. 1 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 June 12 (Box 1)
  - Proverbs 31:28-31, The World's Uncrowned Queen
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1926 May 9 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 May 13 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 May 14 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1935 May 12 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 May 9 (Box 1)
  - Proverbs 31:31, Mothers of To-Day and To-Morrow
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 May 10 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1936 May 10 (Box 1)
  - Ecclesiastes 7:12, The Revolt of Age
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1927 Sept. 18 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Jan. 25 (Box 1)
  - Ecclesiastes 12:13-14, Personal Duty and the Judgement
    - Lambert's Point, Norfolk, Va., 1913 Sept. 21 (Box 1)
    - Clay St., Norfolk, Va., 1915 Oct. 3 (Box 1)
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1917 Aug. 19 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1919 Apr. 6 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1924, Aug. 10 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Oct. 2 (Box 1)
  - Ezekiel 3:22, The Value of Being Alone with God
    - Lambert's Point, Norfolk, Va., 1911 July 30 (Box 1)
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1916 Sept. 3 (Box 1)
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1917 Jan. 27 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1919 Feb. 23 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1922 Oct. 29 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1927 Dec. 18 (Box 1)
    - Moffett Memorial, Danville, Va., 1930 July 27 (Box 1)
    - Episcopal Church, South Boston, Va., 1933 July 9 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1935 June 9 (Box 1)
    - Methodist St., Crewe, Va., 1937 Mar. 22 (Box 1)
  - Daniel 6:10, The Secret of the Greatness of Daniel
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1930 Sept. 21 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Oct. 22 (Box 1)
  - Micah 7:7, My God Will Hear Me
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1918 Aug. 25 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1919 Dec. 28 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1923 July 29 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Feb. 19 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Nov. 26 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1936 Aug. 23 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 Apr. 4 (Box 1)
  - Matthew 5:13, The Purifying Influence
    - Lambert's Point, Norfolk, Va., 1913 May 25 (Box 1)
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1914 Mar. 15 (Box 1)
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1917 Aug. 19 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1920 Oct. 10 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1923 Dec. 9 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1929 Apr. 14 (Box 1)
  - Matthew 7:28-29, Sources of the Authority of Jesus
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1930 Sept. 21 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Aug. 21 (Box 1)
  - Matthew 20:27, He Who Stoops to Conquer
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1935 Jan. 13 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 May 23 (Box 1)
  - Mark 1:12, The Jordan and the Wilderness
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1920 Oct. 10 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1925 Feb. 22 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1929 Sept. 15 (Box 1)
    - First Baptist Church, South Boston, Va., 1933 May 21 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 May 9 (Box 1)
  - Mark 1:14-15, The Bible Idea of Repentance
    - Lambert's Point, Norfolk, Va., 1913 Oct. 5 (Box 1)
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1915 Mar. 28 (Box 1)
    - Emporia, Va., 1915 May 16 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1919 Apr. 17 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1930 Nov. 9 (Box 1)
  - Mark 2:10, Jesus the Friend of Sinners
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1924 Oct. 25 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1929 June 9 (Box 1)
  - Mark 8:25, A New World's Wonder
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1917 Dec. 23 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1920 Jan. 4 (Box 1)
    - Grace, Richmond, Va., 1920 May. 16 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1922 Nov. 19 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1925 Mar. 29 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1927 Dec. 18 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Apr. 8 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1936 Dec. 13 (Box 1)
  - Mark 15:39, Christ's Triumph on the Cross
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1921 Oct. 9 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1930 Apr. 13 (Box 1)
  - Mark 16:15, The Kingdom Extension
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Feb. 28 (Box 1)
  - Luke 2:51-52, The Silent Years of Jesus
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 May 31 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Mar. 11 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 June 13 (Box 1)
  - Luke 9:33, 37-38 Needs for Low-Lands of Sin
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1924 Mar. 23 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1927 Oct. 16 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Mar. 11 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Oct. 11 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Apr. 16 (Box 1)
    - Episcopal Church, South Boston, Va., 1935 July 21 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 May 23 (Box 1)
  - Luke 15:20, The Prodigal's Return
    - Emporia, Va., 1911 Apr. 23 (Box 1)
    - Lambert's Point, Va., 1913 May 18 (Box 1)
    - Cumberland St., Va., 1917 Nov. 4 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1926 Apr. 2 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Feb. 8 (Box 1)
  - John 8:32, Life Through Truth
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1921 Nov. 27 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1923 June 10 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1925 Nov. 22 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Sept. 2 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 June 26 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1938 Jan. 30 (Box 1)
  - John 17:19, The Platform of the Preacher
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1923 Oct. 28 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Nov. 11 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Oct. 28 (Box 1)
  - Acts 2:37, The Church for the World
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1926 Jan. 24 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Jan. 21 (Box 1)
  - Acts 5:15, Life's Unconscious Influence
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Apr. 24 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Dec. 10 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 May 30 (Box 1)
  - Acts 7:56, A Look Inside the Sky
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1931 Dec. 13 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Oct. 9 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1932 Nov. 13 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1935 Feb. 10 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1936 Nov. 29 (Box 1)
  - Acts 13:1, The Successful Church
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1935 Apr. 28 (Box 1)
  - Acts 13:36, The Life that Counts
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1919 Aug. 31 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1923 Sept. 16 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1927 Feb. 6 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 May 13 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 June 12 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 June 10 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 July 4 (Box 1)
  - Romans 5:1, Justification By Faith
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1916 Mar. 19 (Box 1)
  - Romans 5:1-21, What Happened at Aldersgate (no location given) (Box 1)
  - Romans 8:28, A Gospel Tonic, clipped with Psalm 47:9, II Timothy 2:14 and Hebrews 10:35
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1930 Sept. 17 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Aug. 10 (Box 1)
    - South Boston, Va., 1933 Apr. 26 (Box 1)
  - Romans 12:11, A Noble Enthusiasm
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Feb. 21 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1936 Apr. 12 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 May 30 (Box 1)
  - Romans 16:5, The Church in the Home
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1918 May 5 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1922 Apr. 9 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1929 Nov. 24 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Oct. 6 (Box 1)
  - I Corinthians 13:1-6, Making the World Happier
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1915 Aug. 29 (Box 1)
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1917 May 20 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond Va., 1919 June 29 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1924 Jan. 13 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1926 Oct. 21 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Jan. 29 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1935 Feb. 17 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1936 Nov. 29 (Box 1)
  - II Corinthians 6:1, Co-Operation and Good-Will
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 June 14 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 May 30 (Box 1)
  - Galatians 3:1-5, The Folly of the Age
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1915 Dec. 5 (Box 1)
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1918 Nov. 24 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1921 Mar. 6 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1930 May 11 (Box 1)
  - Philippians 3:13-14, Paul's Maxim of Progress
    - Shawnee, Oklahoma, 1907 May (Box 1)
    - Emporia, Va., 1911 May 21 (Box 1)
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1915 Feb. 14 (Box 1)
    - Cumberland St., Norfolk, Va., 1917 Feb. 18 (Box 1)
    - Crew, Va., 1918 June 2 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Sept. 9 (Box 1)
    - Cluster Springs, Va., 1935 May 26 (Box 1)
  - Colossians 1:28, The Sphere of the Minister
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1922 Oct. 8 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1930 Mar. 30 (Box 1)
  - I Timothy 6:19, The Life that Really Is
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1925 Sept. 13 (Box 1)
    - Central, Richmond, Va., 1927 Feb. 20 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1927 Feb. 27 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Apr. 15 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1935 Aug. 25 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va. 1936 Dec. 13 (Box 1)
  - II Timothy 2:14, The Marvellous Memory, clipped with Psalm 47:9, Romans 8:28 and Hebrews 10:35
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1930 Dec. 31 (Box 1)
    - South Boston, Va., 1936 Feb. 29 (Box 1)
  - Hebrews 10:35, Clinging to the Faith, clipped with Psalm 47:9, Romans 8:28 and II Timothy 2:14 (Box 1)
  - Hebrews 12:13, We are all Road-Makers
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1929 July 28 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Dec. 17 (Box 1)
  - I Peter 1:24-25, What Shall I Do With My Life?
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 June 17 (Box 1)
  - I Peter 5:7, Unload Your Cares
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1923 June 3 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1926 Sept. 12 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Aug. 5 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Apr. 17 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 Aug. 27 (Box 1)
  - II Peter 1:16, Strength for the Changing Scenes
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1932 Apr. 10 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1933 June 11 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 June 27 (Box 1)
  - Revelation 2:10, Faithfulness and Its Reward
    - Lambert's Point, Norfolk, Va., 1913 Jan. 12 (Box 1)
    - Clay St., Richmond, Va., 1915 Mar. 23 (Box 1)
    - Emporia, Va., 1915 May 13 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1917 Feb. 25 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1922 July 8 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Apr. 29 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Aug. 26 (Box 1)
    - Shady Grove, Va., 1935 July 19 (Box 1)
  - Revelation 11:15, The Reigning Christ
    - Decatur St., Richmond, Va., 1920 Nov. 13 (Box 1)
    - Ginter Park, Richmond, Va., 1924 Sept. 21 (Box 1)
    - Decatur St., Richmond Va., 1925 Dec. 6 (Box 1)
    - Calvary, Danville, Va., 1928 Dec. 9 (Box 1)
    - Main St., South Boston, Va., 1934 Apr. 1 (Box 1)
    - Methodist Church, Crewe, Va., 1937 Dec. 26 (Box 1)
  - Additional documents, 1936 and undated (Box 1)